rangers.co.uk 2018-12-27

# Privacy Statement - Rangers Football Club, Official Website

#### **1 Introduction**

This policy describes the way in which The Rangers International Football Club PLC aims to repay the trust shown by our valued customers and supporters who have shared their personal data with The Club.

####  **2 About Us**

The Rangers International Football Club PLC (“The Club”) is a sports entertainment company incorporated in Scotland with Company Number SC437060. The registered office is Ibrox Stadium, 150 Edmiston Drive, Glasgow, G51 2XD. The Rangers International Football Club PLC is the controller of all personal data processed by the company and its subsidiary companies; The Rangers Football Club Limited, Rangers Media Limited and Garrion Security Services Limited.

####  **3 Data Protection Officer**

The Club’s Data Protection Officer (DPO) can be contacted with the following details:

The Data Protection Officer  
The Rangers International Football Club PLC  
150 Edmiston Drive  
Glasgow  
G51 2XD

Email:   [dpo@rangers.co.uk  
](mailto:dpo@rangers.co.uk)Tel:       \+ 44 141 580 8500

####  **4 About This Policy**

We will only provide this privacy policy to you once, generally at the start of our relationship with you. However, if this privacy policy is updated substantially, then we may provide you with details of the updated version. You are encouraged to check back regularly for updates.

This policy is dated – 18th May 2018

####  **5 Personal** **Data We May Collect From You**

When you contact us in person, by email, post, telephone or our website, you may provide us with or we may obtain personal data about you, such as information regarding your;

  * personal contact details that allows us to contact you directly such as name, title, email addresses and telephone numbers;
  * date of birth;
  * gender;
  * records of your interactions with us such as telephone conversations, emails and other correspondence and your instructions to us;
  * any credit/debit card and other payment details you provide so that we can receive payments from you and details of the financial transactions with you;
  * use of and movements through our online portal, passwords, personal identification numbers, IP addresses, user names and other IT system identifying information;
  * CCTV footage and other information obtained through electronic means such as swipecard records;
  * records of your attendance at any events or competitions hosted by us;
  * participation in prize draw competitions or raffles provided by us;
  * suggestions offered as part of our customer service feedback campaign;
  * information about your computer including where available your IP address, operating system and browser type;
  * information about your internet usage obtained using a cookie file which is stored on the hard drive of your computer;
  * images in video and/or photographic form and voice recordings; and
  * your marketing preferences so that we know whether and how we should contact you.

####  **6 Special Categories Of Personal Data**

We may also collect, store and use the following “special categories” of more sensitive personal data regarding you:

  * information about your health, including any medical condition, health and sickness records, medical records and health professional information;

We may not collect all of the above types of special category personal data about you. In relation to the special category personal data that we do process we do so on the basis that

  * the processing is necessary for reasons of substantial public interest, on a lawful basis; or
  * based on your explicit consent.

Within the table in section 8, we refer to these as the “special category reasons for processing of your personal data”.

####  **7 Where We Collect Your Personal Data**

We typically collect personal data about our customers and supporters when;

  * you create an account on our Rangers FC website [here](https://www.rangers.talent-sport.co.uk/PagesPublic/Profile/Registration.aspx) or Rangers TV website [here](https://rangers.co.uk/tv/reg) to open an account with The Club to purchase any services or products we offer online;
  * you open an account in person at our ticket office, by telephone or by post;
  * or when you make a query and/or complaint or when you correspond with us by phone, e-mail, official social media channels or in some other way.

If you are a football player we may also collect personal data about you from any club, school or other organisation you are affiliated with or from other referrals such as from coaches or talent scouts.

If you are providing us with family members and emergency contacts or next of kin data then they have a right to know and to be aware of what personal data we hold about them, how we collect it and how we use and may share that information.  Please share this privacy policy with those of them whom you feel are sufficiently mature to understand it.  They also have the same rights as set out in section 14 of this privacy policy.

####  **8 Uses Made Of Your Personal Data**

The table below describes the main purposes for which we process your personal data, the categories of your personal data involved and our lawful basis for being able to do this.

 **Purpose**|  **Personal Data Used**|  **Lawful basis**  
---|---|---  

 **To administer any account(s) you have with us and managing our relationship with you and dealing with payments and any support service or product enquiries made by you.**

|   

All contact and account details, transaction and payment information, Records of your interactions with us, and marketing preferences.

|  

Performance of a contract. This is necessary to enable us to properly manage and administer your contract with us.  

 **To arrange and manage any contracts for the provision of any merchandise, products and/or services.**

|   

All contact and account details.

Transaction and payment information.

|  

Performance of a contract. This is necessary to enable us to properly administer and perform any contract for the provision of merchandise, products or services.  

 **To send you information concerning your purchases.**

|   

All contact and account details.

|  

Performance of a contract. This is necessary to enable us to properly manage and administer your contract with us.  

 **To send you other marketing information we think you might find relevant or which you have requested from us, including our newsletters, information about upcoming matches, events, products and information about our commercial partners.**

|   

All contact and account details and marketing preferences.

|  

Where you have given us your consent to do so.  

 **To answer your queries or complaints.**

|   

Contact details and records of your interactions with us.

|  

We have a legitimate interest to provide complaint handling services to you in case there are any issues with your account or contract.  

 **Retention of records.**

|   

All the personal information we collect.

|  

We have a legitimate interest in retaining records whilst they may be required in relation to complaints or claims. We need to retain records to properly administer and manage your account and in some cases, we may have legal or regulatory obligations to retain records.

We process special category personal data on the basis of the “special category reasons for processing of your personal data” referred to in section 6 of this policy.  
  
---|---|---  

 **Your usage of our IT systems and online portals.**

|   

IP addresses and cookies.

|  

We have a legitimate interest to ensure that our IT systems are secure and efficient.  

 **To conduct data analytics studies to better understand event attendance and trends within the sport.**

|   

Records of your attendance at football matches, soccer schools and any other events that you choose to attend.

|  

We have a legitimate interest in doing so to ensure that our customer offers are targeted and relevant.  

 **To ensure that the content on our website(s) is presented in the most effective manner for you and your computer.**

|   

IP address, operating system and browser type.

|  

We have a legitimate Interest to provide the best possible user experience when browsing our website(s) or watching video content.  

 **For the provision of stadium security and the minimisation of crime and disorder.**

|   

Images in video and/or photographic form.

|  

We have a legal obligation to provide a safe environment and will use CCTV recording as a        method of doing so.  

 **For the promotion of products and events.**

|   

Images in video and/or photographic form.

|  

It is a condition of the contract to purchase a match ticket that you are aware that we use photography and video recording to promote our products and events.  

 **To comply with health and safety requirements.**

|   

Records of attendance.

|  

We have a legal obligation and a legitimate interest to provide you and other members of our organisation with a safe environment in which to participate in or attend sporting events.  
  
For some of your personal data you will have a legal, contractual or other requirement or obligation for you to provide us with your personal data.  If you do not provide us with the requested personal data we may not be able to properly perform our contract with you or comply with legal obligations.

Where you have given us your consent to use your personal data in a particular manner, you have the right to withdraw this consent at any time, which you may do by contacting us as per the details outlined in section 3 of this policy.

Please note however that the withdrawal of your consent will not affect any use of the data made before you withdrew your consent and we may still be entitled to hold and process the relevant personal data to the extent that we are entitled to do so on a legal basis other than your consent.  Withdrawing consent may also have the same effects as not providing the information in the first place, for example we may no longer be able to provide certain customer benefits to you.

####  **9 Direct Marketing**

From time to time we may contact you by email, post or SMS with information about products and services we believe may be relevant to you.

We will only send marketing communications to you in accordance with the marketing preferences you set. You can update your communication preferences or unsubscribe at any time [here](https://www.rangers.talent-sport.co.uk/PagesLogin/Profile/updateProfile.aspx).

####  **10 How We May Share Your Personal Data**

We share your personal data with the following parties:

  * Any party approved by you;
  * To any football governing bodies: to allow them to properly administer the sport on a local, regional and national level;
  * Other service providers: for example, email marketing specialists, payment processors, data analysis, CCTV contractors, promotional advisors, contractors or suppliers and IT services (including CRM, website, video and teleconference services);
  * The Government: where we are required to do so by law or to assist with their investigations or initiatives;
  * Police, law enforcement and security services: when we are required to assist with the investigation and prevention of crime and the protection of national security.

We do not disclose personal data to anyone else except as set out above.

####  **11 Profiling and Automated Decision Making**

The Club does not perform any profiling or automated decision making that has a significant or legal effect.

####  **12 Transferring Your Personal Data Internationally**

The personal data we collect may be transferred to and stored in countries outside of the UK and the European Economic Area. Some of these jurisdictions require different levels of protection in respect of personal data and, in certain instances, the laws in those countries may be less protective than the jurisdiction you are typically resident in. We will take all reasonable steps to ensure that your personal information is only used in accordance with this privacy policy and applicable data protection laws and is respected and kept secure. Where we employ an organisation to process your data on our behalf we will put in place appropriate safeguards as required under data protection laws.  For further details please contact the Data Protection Officer using the details in section 3

####  **13 How Long Do We Keep Your Personal Data**

The duration for which we retain your personal data will differ depending on the type of information and the reason why we collected it from you. However, in some cases personal data may be retained on a long-term basis: for example, personal data that we need to retain for legal purposes will normally be retained in accordance with usual commercial practice and regulatory requirements.  Generally, where there is no legal requirement we retain all physical and electronic records for a period of [6] years after your last contract with us.  Exceptions to this rule are:

  * CCTV records which are held for no more than 28 days unless we need to preserve the records for the purpose of prevention and detection of crime;
  * Information that may be relevant to personal injury claims, or discrimination claims may be retained until the limitation period for those types of claims has expired. For personal injury or discrimination claims this can be an extended period as the limitation period might not start to run until a long time after the event.

It is important to ensure that the personal data we hold about you is accurate and up-to-date, and you should let us know if anything changes, for example if you change your phone number or email address

####  **14 Your Rights**

You have the following rights concerning your personal data. If you wish to exercise any of your rights, please contact the Data Protection Officer on the details listed in section 3 of this privacy policy.

|   
---|---  
 **Right of access**|  You have the right to obtain confirmation from The Club as to whether or not personal data concerning you is being processed, and, where that is the case, access to that personal data.  
 **Right to rectification**|  You have the right to oblige The Club to rectify inaccurate personal data concerning you. Taking into account the purposes of the processing, you have the right to have incomplete personal data completed by providing a supplementary statement.  
 **Right to erasure (right to be forgotten)**|  You have the right (under certain circumstances, but not all) to oblige The Club to erase personal data concerning you.  
 **Right to restriction of processing**|  You have the right (under certain circumstances, but not all) to oblige The Club to restrict processing of your personal data. For example, you may request this if you are contesting the accuracy of personal data held about you.  
 **Right to data portability**|  You have the right (under certain circumstances, but not all) to oblige The Club to provide you with the personal data about you which you have provided to The Club in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format.

You also have the right to oblige The Club to transmit those data to another controller.  
  
 **Right to withdraw consent**|  If the lawful basis for processing is consent, you have the right to withdraw that consent.  
 **Right to object to direct marketing**|  Where your personal data are processed for direct marketing purposes, you have the right to object at any time to processing of your personal data for marketing, which includes profiling to the extent that it is related to such direct marketing.  
 **Rights in relation to automated decision making and profiling**|  The Club does not perform any automated decision-making based on personal data that produces legal effects or similarly significantly affects you.  
  
####  **15 Your Right To Lodge A Complaint**

If you wish to exercise any of your rights concerning your personal data, please contact The Club’s Data Protection Officer in the first instance. The DPO will ensure your request is handled in a professional and timely manner. If however, you are not satisfied with the response you receive, you have the right to lodge a complaint with the supervisory authority. For the UK, the details are listed below:

Information Commissioner’s Office

Wycliffe House  
Water Lane  
Wilmslow  
Cheshire  
SK9 5AF

Tel:       03031 231 113  
Fax:      01625 524 510
